<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on AI-Lab</title>
    <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on AI-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ailab-research.github.io/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Approach to Flapping Flight Analysis Published in Physica D</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-12-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-12-journal/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan and Dr Lai&amp;rsquo;s latest study, &amp;lsquo;Accelerating Flapping Flight Analysis: Reducing CFD Dependency with a Hybrid Decision Tree Approach for Swift Velocity Predictions&amp;rsquo;, has been published in Physica D: Nonlinear Phenomena. The research introduces a novel framework combining signal decomposition and decision tree algorithms, reducing computational time by up to 75% while maintaining high accuracy. Validated with damselfly data, this approach accelerates flapping flight analysis and supports the efficient design of micro air vehicles (MAVs), offering a scalable solution for future aerodynamic research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Insights Featured on AIP Publishing Showcase</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-05-kudos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-05-kudos/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan and his research team have been recognised by the American Institute of Physics (AIP), with their latest study selected as a feature article on Kudos&amp;rsquo; Showcase platform. The research, titled &amp;lsquo;Balancing Thrust and Energy Efficiency: Optimised Asymmetric Flapping Inspired by Batoid Locomotion&amp;rsquo;, explores how the unique swimming motion of stingrays can inspire more efficient designs for underwater vehicles.&#xA;By using advanced computer simulations, the team discovered that shorter, quicker downstrokes—similar to how stingrays naturally move—enhance thrust while reducing energy consumption.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Awarded Outstanding Reviewer Award</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-bb/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan has been honoured with the Outstanding Reviewer Award 2024, a prestigious accolade recognising his significant contributions to academic research. Congratulations!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Published in Physics of Fluids: Biomimetic Propulsion Study</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-journal/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan, Dr Lai and their team have published a study in Physics of Fluids exploring how stingray-like asymmetric flapping enhances underwater propulsion. Using a NACA 0012 hydrofoil at a Reynolds number of 10,000 and NSGA-II optimisation, they identified six optimal motion patterns with brief downstrokes. Their findings reveal how harmonic tuning influences vortex dynamics, closely resembling natural swimming. This research provides key insights for designing efficient biomimetic aquatic robots, advancing underwater propulsion technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Talented Individuals Join The Lab</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-01-15-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-01-15-members/</guid>
      <description>Six bachelor&amp;rsquo;s students have joined the lab. Welcome aboard!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Students Shine at the 2024 Innovation Arena</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-12-09-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-12-09-startup/</guid>
      <description>Under the guidance of Dr Lan, a team of four students participated in the 2024 Innovation Arena (興創競技場) and secured the prestigious Infinite Potential Award in the Creative Concept category. The competition, organised by the University&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Industry-Academia Collaboration, aims to inspire students and staff to transform their academic expertise and innovative ideas into entrepreneurial solutions tailored to industry needs. By bridging innovation and practical application, the initiative fosters global perspectives and highlights the tangible value of academic research in the real world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hsing-Yun Huang and Thanh Kim Hua Earn Honours at CSME</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-11-17-csme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-11-17-csme/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan’s students, Hsing-Yun Huang and Thanh Kim Hua, have achieved remarkable success at the CSME’s Student Paper Competition. Both were awarded Honourable Mentions for their outstanding research contributions, showcasing innovative approaches and technical excellence. Their achievements highlight the dedication and talent nurtured within Dr Lan&amp;rsquo;s mentorship, bringing pride to their academic community. Congratulations to both students!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakthrough in Manta-like Swimming Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-10-01-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-10-01-journal/</guid>
      <description>A big congratulations to Dr Lai&amp;rsquo;s team and Dr Lan on the successful publication of their groundbreaking research in Physics of Fluids! Their study explores how manta-like swimming dynamics, specifically asymmetric motion parameters, can greatly enhance the efficiency of underwater unmanned vehicles. By investigating the effects of varying angles of attack and stroke duration, the research provides key insights into maximising thrust and propulsion efficiency. This work not only advances our understanding of aquatic biomechanics but also paves the way for innovative designs in biomimetic underwater technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Talented Individuals Join The Lab</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-09-01-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-09-01-members/</guid>
      <description>Four postgraduate students have joined the lab. Welcome aboard!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Chairs Insect Flight Symposium at Kyoto Congress</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-08-29-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-08-29-ice/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan recently chaired a symposium at the 27th International Congress of Entomology held in Kyoto, where he and his research team presented three papers on insect flight. Their studies, contributing substantial insights into the aerodynamics of insect wings, garnered considerable interest among the global entomological community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Awarded IOP Trusted Reviewer Status</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-06-12-iop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-06-12-iop/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan has been honoured with the IOP Trusted Reviewer Status, a prestigious accolade recognising his significant contributions to peer review. Congratulations!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Featured in Programme Newsletter, Issue 75</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-03-21-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-03-21-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan has been featured in Issue 75 of the Newsletter of the Programe in Aeronautics &amp;amp; Astronautics and Thermal Science &amp;amp; Fluid Dynamics, where his work at the AI-Lab is highlighted. This publication showcases the latest research and developments within the field, with a particular focus on Dr Lan&amp;rsquo;s contributions to advancing knowledge in aeronautics and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Paper Published in &#39;Ocean Engineering&#39;: A Leap Forward</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-01-12-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-01-12-journal/</guid>
      <description>Heartfelt congratulations to Dr Lai&amp;rsquo;s team and Dr Lan on their seminal publication in &amp;lsquo;Ocean Engineering&amp;rsquo;. Their paper, &amp;lsquo;Strouhal number impact on propulsion efficiency in fully-active oscillating foils: Unpacking frequency, amplitude, and velocity relationships&amp;rsquo;, is not just a leap forward in marine technology but also holds immense potential for transforming oscillating foils technology across diverse realms, from the depths of the ocean to the intricacies of flapping flight.&#xA;For more information please refer to https://doi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Talented Individuals Join The Lab</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-12-28-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-12-28-members/</guid>
      <description>Six bachelor&amp;rsquo;s students have joined the lab. Welcome aboard!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Odour Tracking Study Presented at CSME Conference</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-12-01-csme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-12-01-csme/</guid>
      <description>After presenting their preliminary research on odour tracking at the 40th CSME Conference in Changhua, Dr Lan and lab members Kim Thanh Hua and Hsing-Yun Huang balanced their celebratory moments with intellectual engagement. They interacted with scholars from various universities, exchanging ideas on biomimetics and enriching their academic perspectives.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preliminary Flapping Wing Study Presented at AASRC Conference</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-11-25-aasrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-11-25-aasrc/</guid>
      <description>At the 65th AASRC Conference in Taichung, Dr Lan and his master&amp;rsquo;s student, Ching-Chan Huang, presented early research into the interaction between two separate flapping wings. This preliminary work contributes to comprehending the flight mechanisms in insect groups.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Four Talented Individuals Join The Lab</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-09-01-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-09-01-members/</guid>
      <description>Four postgraduate students have joined the lab. Welcome aboard!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan and Dr Lai Collaborate to Unveil Conceptual Butterfly-Inspired Robot</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-08-31-aris/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-08-31-aris/</guid>
      <description>At The 11th International Conference on Advanced Robotics and Intelligent Systems (ARIS 2023) conference in Taipei, Dr Lan and Dr Yu-Hsiang Lai revealed their groundbreaking research on butterfly-inspired robots. This biomimetic study not only deepens our understanding of biological flight mechanisms but also holds promise for advancing unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Discusses Interdisciplinary Education in Ministry of Education Interview</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-07-25-edu-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-07-25-edu-interview/</guid>
      <description>In a recent interview with the Ministry of Education, Dr Lan highlighted the innovative cross-disciplinary research at the Enable Center, founded by Professor Charles W. Tu. The centre gained attention last year when Dr Lan collaborated with Dr Ching-Wen Tan on an unprecedented project that merged the fields of entomology and mechanical engineering. Intrigued by the novel approach, Professor Tu asked Dr Lan to join him for this exclusive interview.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Invited as Adjudicator for the 9th NCKU Mechanical Project Exhibition</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-06-17-ncku-exhibition/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-06-17-ncku-exhibition/</guid>
      <description>The Mechanical Project Exhibition returned on June 17th at National Cheng Kung University (NCKU). 39 student teams participated, showcasing their project-based learning and integrating theoretical knowledge from various mechanical engineering fields. The event highlighted creativity and collaboration, inspiring future engineers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan&#39;s Team Unveils 3 Cutting-Edge Research at AMAM Conference</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-06-07-amam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-06-07-amam/</guid>
      <description>In a collaborative effort, Dr Lan and his team made significant contributions to the 11th International Symposium on Adaptive Motion of Animals and Machines (AMAM) in Kobe, Japan. Their groundbreaking research delved into the realms of aerodynamics and odour tracking, providing valuable insights at the intersection of animal locomotion and technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan to Give Keynote Speech at National Defense University</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-02-24-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-02-24-speech/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan delivers an inspiring speech on the application of odour sensing at National Defense University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Six Talented Individuals Join The Lab</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-02-13-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2023-02-13-members/</guid>
      <description>We have welcomed a master&amp;rsquo;s student, four bachelor&amp;rsquo;s students, and an exchange student to the lab. Welcome aboard!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Invited to Give Talk at CSME Conference</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-12-02-csme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-12-02-csme/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan gives a speech entitled &amp;lsquo;Machine Learning in Flapping Flight Transient Acceleration Modelling&amp;rsquo; at CSME 2022.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three Talented Individuals Join The Lab</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-09-01-members/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-09-01-members/</guid>
      <description>Three postgraduate students have joined the lab. Welcome aboard!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Journal Paper on Drones</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-08-17-drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-08-17-drones/</guid>
      <description>Great news! The paper titled &amp;lsquo;A Neural Network Approach to Estimate Transient Aerodynamic Properties of a Flapping Wing System&amp;rsquo; by Lan et al. has been published in the journal Drones. Congratulations!&#xA;For more information please refer to https://doi.org/10.3390/drones6080210.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Reported by AIP</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-30-aip-scilight/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-30-aip-scilight/</guid>
      <description>The research conducted in the paper &amp;lsquo;Optimal thrust efficiency for a tandem wing in forward flight using varied hindwing kinematics of a damselfly&amp;rsquo; was reported by AIP Scilight, congratulations.&#xA;For more information please refer to https://aip.scitation.org/doi/full/10.1063/10.0012500.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Accepted by Physics of Fluids</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-02-paper-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-02-paper-accepted/</guid>
      <description>The paper &amp;lsquo;Optimal thrust efficiency for a tandem wing in forward flight using varied hindwing kinematics of a damselfly&amp;rsquo; was accepted by the journal Physics of Fluids, congratulations.&#xA;For more information please refer to https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0093208.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lab Website Launched</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-01-website-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-01-website-launched/</guid>
      <description>The &amp;lsquo;Advanced Integration Laboratory (AI-Lab)&amp;rsquo; will be establish on 01 August 2022. To make more people understand our works, we launched this site for showing our research projects and results.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
