<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Awards on AI-Lab</title>
    <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/categories/awards/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Awards on AI-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ailab-research.github.io/categories/awards/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Receives Meritorious Research Award at TCUS Innovation Competition</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-12-08-tcus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-12-08-tcus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Lan was recognised with a Meritorious Research Award in this year’s Young Scholars Innovation Competition organised by the Taiwan Comprehensive University System (臺灣綜合大學系統). His research highlights a cross-domain biomimetic propulsion concept that leverages AI techniques to enhance energy efficiency in both aerial and aquatic environments. By drawing on natural movement strategies and translating them into engineered designs, this work demonstrates how bio-inspired thinking can open new possibilities for multifunctional propulsion, a direction that aligned strongly with the competition’s emphasis on innovative academic contributions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qi-Sheng Huang Earns Honourable Mention at CSME Conference</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-12-05-csme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-12-05-csme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At this year’s CSME Conference, Qi-Sheng Huang received an Honourable Mention (佳作) in the student paper competition for research conducted under the supervision of Dr Lan. The study explores a pursuit strategy inspired by the silkmoth’s distinctive tracking behaviour. By translating this biological mechanism into an engineered system, the team demonstrated notable gains in both efficiency and accuracy, underscoring the value of nature-inspired approaches in robotic guidance and control.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/25/12_csme.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Graduate Team Wins Merit Award in IMBD</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-11-22-imbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-11-22-imbd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A graduate student team supervised by Dr Lan, led by Yen-Cheng Chang alongside two fellow members, has received a Merit Award (優等獎) in the National Intelligent Manufacturing Big Data Analytics Competition (IMBD, 全國智慧製造大數據分析競賽). Their project showcased effective use of artificial intelligence and big data techniques, demonstrating strong analytical capability and innovative problem-solving in data-driven applications.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/25/11_imbd.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Team Receives Honourable Mention for Bio-Inspired Ray Project</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-11-22-capstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-11-22-capstone/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three undergraduate students, supervised by Dr Lan, have received an honourable mention (佳作) in the Capstone Project (機械設計與製作專題) competition. Their work focused on a bio-inspired ray system, investigating the propulsion principles of ray-like motion and presenting a functional design that highlights the potential of biomimetic concepts in underwater robotic development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/25/11_capstone.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ming-Han Wu Takes Third Place in AASRC Best Paper Award</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-11-15-aasrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-11-15-aasrc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ming-Han Wu, with co-author Yi-Hsi Yeh, supervised by Dr Lan, has secured third place in the Best Paper Award competition at the AASRC Conference. Their study examined how variations in wing phase shift affect thrust generation in a robotic dragonfly, offering insights that contribute to ongoing research in bio-inspired flight.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/25/11_aasrc.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two Teams Win Maker Potential Award at the 2025 Makerthon</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-09-13-makerthon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-09-13-makerthon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two student teams, supervised by Dr Lan, won the Maker Potential Award (創客潜力獎) at the 2025 Makerthon – Technology Empowerment × Future-Making Competition (創客松-科技賦能X自造未來競賽). One team developed an innovative aerial drone, while the other created a submersible vehicle inspired by marine engineering, both demonstrating the creative spirit and technical skills celebrated by the event.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/25/09_makerthon.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1st Place at the 2025 Ocean Challenge</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-09-02-ocean/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-09-02-ocean/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three undergraduates, supervised by Dr Lan, won 1st place at the 2025 Ocean Challenge (臺灣海洋國際青年論壇) with a manta ray-inspired underwater vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/25/09_ocean.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nature-Inspired Designs Win Awards in Bionic Design Competition</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-07-04-biomimicry/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-07-04-biomimicry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the guidance of Dr Lan, two student teams from the lab took part in the 2025 Bionic Design Competition (仿生設計競賽), an event showcasing nature-inspired innovation for sustainability. Among 78 entries, both teams received awards for their nature-inspired designs: one received a Merit Award for their bio-inspired stingray underwater vehicle, while the other was awarded Honourable Mention for a butterfly-inspired micro air vehicle. The competition, supported by Biomimicry Taiwan, promotes sustainable innovation rooted in natural principles, addressing global challenges from disaster resilience to environmental health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Awarded Outstanding Reviewer Award</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-bb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-bb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Lan has been honoured with the Outstanding Reviewer Award 2024, a prestigious accolade recognising his significant contributions to academic research. Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/25/03_bb.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Students Shine at the 2024 Innovation Arena</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-12-09-startup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-12-09-startup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Under the guidance of Dr Lan, a team of four students participated in the 2024 Innovation Arena (興創競技場) and secured the prestigious Infinite Potential Award in the Creative Concept category. The competition, organised by the University&amp;rsquo;s Centre for Industry-Academia Collaboration, aims to inspire students and staff to transform their academic expertise and innovative ideas into entrepreneurial solutions tailored to industry needs. By bridging innovation and practical application, the initiative fosters global perspectives and highlights the tangible value of academic research in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hsing-Yun Huang and Thanh Kim Hua Earn Honours at CSME</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-11-17-csme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-11-17-csme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Lan’s students, Hsing-Yun Huang and Thanh Kim Hua, have achieved remarkable success at the CSME’s Student Paper Competition. Both were awarded Honourable Mentions (佳作) for their outstanding research contributions, showcasing innovative approaches and technical excellence. Their achievements highlight the dedication and talent nurtured within Dr Lan&amp;rsquo;s mentorship, bringing pride to their academic community. Congratulations to both students!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/24/11_csme.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dr Lan Awarded IOP Trusted Reviewer Status</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-06-12-iop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-06-12-iop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dr Lan has been honoured with the IOP Trusted Reviewer Status, a prestigious accolade recognising his significant contributions to peer review. Congratulations!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ailab-research.github.io/images/24/06_iop.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
