<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on AI-Lab</title>
    <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/tags/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on AI-Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://ailab-research.github.io/tags/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Innovative Approach to Flapping Flight Analysis Published in Physica D</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-12-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-12-journal/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan and Dr Lai&amp;rsquo;s latest study, &amp;lsquo;Accelerating Flapping Flight Analysis: Reducing CFD Dependency with a Hybrid Decision Tree Approach for Swift Velocity Predictions&amp;rsquo;, has been published in Physica D: Nonlinear Phenomena. The research introduces a novel framework combining signal decomposition and decision tree algorithms, reducing computational time by up to 75% while maintaining high accuracy. Validated with damselfly data, this approach accelerates flapping flight analysis and supports the efficient design of micro air vehicles (MAVs), offering a scalable solution for future aerodynamic research.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Published in Physics of Fluids: Biomimetic Propulsion Study</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2025-03-04-journal/</guid>
      <description>Dr Lan, Dr Lai and their team have published a study in Physics of Fluids exploring how stingray-like asymmetric flapping enhances underwater propulsion. Using a NACA 0012 hydrofoil at a Reynolds number of 10,000 and NSGA-II optimisation, they identified six optimal motion patterns with brief downstrokes. Their findings reveal how harmonic tuning influences vortex dynamics, closely resembling natural swimming. This research provides key insights for designing efficient biomimetic aquatic robots, advancing underwater propulsion technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakthrough in Manta-like Swimming Efficiency</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-10-01-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-10-01-journal/</guid>
      <description>A big congratulations to Dr Lai&amp;rsquo;s team and Dr Lan on the successful publication of their groundbreaking research in Physics of Fluids! Their study explores how manta-like swimming dynamics, specifically asymmetric motion parameters, can greatly enhance the efficiency of underwater unmanned vehicles. By investigating the effects of varying angles of attack and stroke duration, the research provides key insights into maximising thrust and propulsion efficiency. This work not only advances our understanding of aquatic biomechanics but also paves the way for innovative designs in biomimetic underwater technologies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Paper Published in &#39;Ocean Engineering&#39;: A Leap Forward</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-01-12-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2024-01-12-journal/</guid>
      <description>Heartfelt congratulations to Dr Lai&amp;rsquo;s team and Dr Lan on their seminal publication in &amp;lsquo;Ocean Engineering&amp;rsquo;. Their paper, &amp;lsquo;Strouhal number impact on propulsion efficiency in fully-active oscillating foils: Unpacking frequency, amplitude, and velocity relationships&amp;rsquo;, is not just a leap forward in marine technology but also holds immense potential for transforming oscillating foils technology across diverse realms, from the depths of the ocean to the intricacies of flapping flight.&#xA;For more information please refer to https://doi.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Journal Paper on Drones</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-08-17-drones/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-08-17-drones/</guid>
      <description>Great news! The paper titled &amp;lsquo;A Neural Network Approach to Estimate Transient Aerodynamic Properties of a Flapping Wing System&amp;rsquo; by Lan et al. has been published in the journal Drones. Congratulations!&#xA;For more information please refer to https://doi.org/10.3390/drones6080210.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Accepted by Physics of Fluids</title>
      <link>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-02-paper-accepted/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://ailab-research.github.io/news/2022-06-02-paper-accepted/</guid>
      <description>The paper &amp;lsquo;Optimal thrust efficiency for a tandem wing in forward flight using varied hindwing kinematics of a damselfly&amp;rsquo; was accepted by the journal Physics of Fluids, congratulations.&#xA;For more information please refer to https://doi.org/10.1063/5.0093208.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
